blottr.com 2013-08-09

# Privacy Policy News 24 - 7 | Blottr

Your privacy is really important to us. We have provided this privacy statement explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used by Blottr and Blottr partners.

Personally identifiable information

Any information gathered by Blottr is used to enhance and customise your Blottr experience, and is not shared or sold to any third parties, except where expressly provisioned for in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service.

Blottr retains the right to view personal information provided by our users for the purposes of fixing issues, and to look for copyrighted or other inappropriate material should we decide to do so. Examples of the types of personally identifiable information that may be collected include: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number and information about your interests in and use of various products and services.

You may also submit information about other people through Blottr. For example, you might submit a person's name and e-mail address to send an email to that person suggesting they engage in content you have posted on Blottr.

Certain parts of our Site are accessible only to those who provide us with the requested personally identifiable information. For example, to create a news story or publish a photo or video, you will need to be a registered user and logged into Blottr.

Non-personally identifiable information

We, our service providers, advertisers and partners may collect various types of non-personally identifiable information when you visit our Site. An example of the types of non-personally identifiable information we may collect include: current Internet protocol address and type of browser you are using (e.g., Firefox, Safari or Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS), the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., BT, Virgin Media or Tiscali), the web pages you have visited, the content you have accessed and the advertisements you have been shown and/or clicked on.

How We Use the Information

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our products and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, to offer you other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you, to enforce the legal terms that govern your use of our Site, and/or for the purposes for which you provided the information.

Importantly, as part of our Terms of Service we use this information to communicate with you to let you know when someone has engaged or made a connection with you through our Site. Examples of this are notifing you when another user has collaborated on a news story or post either originated by you or edited by you, or when another user directly sends you a private message through Blottr.

We will contact you to notify you of any material changes to our Terms of Service, product or technology platform, when we make changes to our user agreements, or to fulfill a request by you for online communication. We will also use this information to contact you about your account with us, should we need to.

We may use the information that you provide about yourself and others to enable us, from time to time, to offer products or services from selected chosen partners and advertisers. You are able to opt-out of receiving information and offers from third parties should you decide.

We may share, upon request, your information with strategic partners with whom Blottr have a deeper, strategic relationship. Their use of information supplied by Blottr will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

The information we collect in connection with our online communities is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate participation in these online communities.

If you choose to submit content for publication we may publish your screen name and other information you have provided to us. You are able to decide what information we display, however your name or chosen username will always be displayed and associated with any content you post on Blottr.

We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our Site, to deliver more relevant marketing messages and advertisements and to enable us to personalise your Blottr experience. We may use this information to analyse usage and user behaviour across our Site.

Notifications

It is our policy to provide notifications by email, whether such notifications are required by law or for the purpose of notifying users when another person has i) added to or edited a news story you originate, ii) a registered community member has flagged content created by you for removal iii) another user has sent you a private message on the Blottr platform or iv) to provide relevant marketing material from Blottr or selected partners.

You may choose not to continue receiving marketing emails from Blottr or selcted partners by unsubscribing to any of the marketing emails you receive.

In accepting our Terms of Service, you agree as per your usage of the Site that any other platform-triggered notifications from Blottr are mandatory and cannot be turned off.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, Blottr reserves the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to our users.

Information Sharing and Disclosure

We may disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order. We also may disclose such information in response to a request from an officer of the law, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our terms of use, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Site and applicable laws or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements.

In addition, we may transfer personally identifiable information about you if we, or one of our business units, are acquired by, sold to, or merged with another entity.

Our agents and contractors who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this privacy statement by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for us.

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorised disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this privacy statement.

We may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties whose practices are not covered by this privacy statement (e.g., other marketers, magazine publishers, retailers, participatory databases, and non-profit organisations) that want to market products or services to you. If Blottr shares personally identifiable information, it will provide you with an opportunity to opt out or block such uses either at the point of submission of your personally identifiable information or prior to any such disclosure.

If you have signed up to receive our e-mails and prefer not to receive marketing information any longer, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions provided on any marketing e-mail you receive from this Site.

To provide visitors with additional or more relevant product and service opportunities, we may share non-personally identifiable information with third parties.

Security

To prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We believe in protecting your information just as we would want our own information protected.

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Blottr will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

Whilst Blottr stores passwords, to protect your security we do not have access to or visibility of any passwords entered into our system.

Should a user forget their password, Blottr will send an email to the users’ personal email address provided at the time of registration, or the latest email address provided by you should it have changed since registration, with a link to reset your password. You will not be able to use the same password and will be required to use a new one.

Child Protection

We do not offer services to, or target, persons under the age of 13. In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we will purge any information we receive from people we believe to be children under 13 from our database and cancel the corresponding accounts.

Advertising Practices

We, our service providers, advertisers or partners may collect various types of non-personally identifiable information when you interact with us or visit our Site. The non-personally identifiable information collected may be combined with information from other sources and/or shared with third parties.

The non-personally identifiable information collected may be used to improve the design and content of our sites, and to enable us to personalise your Blottr experience. This information may also be used to provide you with additional product and service opportunities and to make inferences about your interests in order to deliver more relevant marketing messages and advertisements,

Cookies & Web Beacons

To enhance your online experience, we use "cookies" or similar technologies. Cookies are text files placed in your computer's browser to store your preferences. Cookies do not contain personally identifiable information; however, once you choose to furnish a site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use cookies to understand site and Internet usage and to improve or customize the content, offerings or advertisements on our sites. For example, we may use cookies to personalise your experience on our Site (e.g., to recognise you by name when you return to us or to save your password in password-protected areas) We also may use cookies to help us deliver relevant advertising.

We, our third party service providers, advertisers or our partners also may use cookies to manage and measure the performance of advertisements displayed on or delivered through Blottr.com.

We, our third party service providers, advertiser or our partners may also use "web beacons" or clear .gifs, or similar technologies, which are small pieces of code placed on a web page, to monitor the behaviour and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page. For example, web beacons may be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page.

You can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies, require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Blocking all cookies will affect your online experience and may prevent you from enjoying the full features offered by Blottr.

Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers, and Sponsors

Blottr may contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

Blottr may offer content (e.g., competitions, polls or promotions) that are sponsored by or co-branded with identified third parties. By virtue of these relationships, the third parties may obtain personally identifiable information that visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the site activity. We have no control over these third parties' use of this information. The site will notify you at the time of requesting personally identifiable information if these third parties will obtain such information.

We also use the services of reputable third parties to provide us with data collection, reporting and ad response measurement, as well as to assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may view, edit or set their own cookies. We, our third party service providers, advertisers and/or partners may also place web beacons for these third parties. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this privacy statement. For more information on how our sites may use third-party ad servers and your ability to opt-out of targeted advertising from such third party ad servers, please see the section below on "Third Party Ad Servers".

How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information

You can access your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by logging in and "Editing" your Account.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. The main form of identity management is your e-mail address. Please always use a valid and up-to-date e-mail address.

You may also send an e-mail to the following e-mail address requesting access to or correction of your personally identifiable information. For verification purposes please include your first name, last name, e-mail address and the password you use for such service. E-mail: [privacy@blottr.com](mailto:privacy@blottr.com)

How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about the online privacy statement for this site or its implementation you may contact us at [privacy@blottr.com](mailto:privacy@blottr.com)

Updates & Effective Date

From time to time, we may update this privacy statement. We will notify you about material changes in the way we treat personally identifiable information by placing a notice on our site and sending a direct email to registered users’email addresses. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this policy so that you always know what information we collect, how we use it, and with whom we share it.

The Privacy Statement on this Site was last updated on January 28, 2010.
